the end of the draft feel good
about submitting his name. James
sorry James the state of yard
lineup goes with your 2D coming
into into the weekend Did they
not did that allow you guys to
maybe take some more
developmental prospects today
especially that you can just
spend this this year you know uh
smoothing out their rough edges.
Yeah you you know I feel good
about these guys that we've
we've selected or have in
fact agreed to terms with an
undrafted college free agency uh
competing for spots
and and doing their part to
level up our play and the
competition across the roster Uh
while at the same time knowing
that there's going to be some
development required for sure
and uh uh really knowing that
those guys are are going to pour
into it and you know we're not
going to invite anybody into
this building uh who isn't a
strong match for it You know the
the idea that those that we have
uh are in fact built to thrive
and be the best versions of of
themselves because
of the the environment and and
that alignment with what they're
actually built of and
made of I think is uh is really
clear in this crop. Go ahead
back to Parker a who found him b
b in terms of linebacker off
ball
linebacker philosophy looking
back at your time with the Rams
rams where things stand now
through two draft cycles in
terms of the priority at the
offball linebacker position
where you have found value how
would you evaluate that you know
so to go to the first portion of
that question just like with any
uh the prospects it typically
comes from uh the the area scout
and so A-Rob did a great job
bringing his name to the table
early in the down and had a ton
of heat uh which ult ultimately
funneled uh upward uh for our
cross check
to then our undrafted college
college free agency committee
and then ultimately
through that uh layered portion
of interest uh up to coordinator
level myself and Liam so So
that's kind of the the
transition of uh
ultimately his viewing and
interest level But um as it
relates to the second
portion question uh uh certainly
think you can find quality
players at a ton of different
intervals and we certainly had
success towards the latter half
and uh
latter portion of drafts and
also undrafted college free
agency in Los Angeles uh
specifically at the linebacker
position Uh but nonetheless I
think that instincts are
certainly going to be something
that reigns supreme in that
space knowing that a lot happens
fast and in the the specific
interest of of of Parker Uh that
stands out in a
real way. Would you like Bo
Wesley Williams? A ton I mean
that dude gets after it He's got
uh the make that aligns with
everything everything that we
covet And the fact
that he's able to disrupt both
the run and the pass uh is
really a helpful piece piece to
our cause
because we don't want to be too
one-dimensional defensively and
in particular we want to stop
the run and uh knowing that he
can do his part to disrupt
disrupt uh while at the same
time uh maintain uh fundamentals
and techniques Uh it's a really
exciting piece.
Five block kicks for him too. Oh
it's impressive And I know like
uh I went and watched those
specifically towards the half of
last week week cuz I hadn't
stumbled into
them I just stumbled into uh
something that we we called Did
You Know And it was a little
nugget
that our analytics crew uh puts
together on each player And so
as I'm just reading I was like
you know what I've watched all
of his defensive snaps all of
his games but let me go
watch these kick block kicks
specifically And uh and then it
forced me to go back and
actually watch
watch his special team snaps And
even on uh a number of the kicks
that he didn't block he was
creating disruption and getting
really close in a lot of of
instances as well So that's
certainly uh more than just uh
happen stance It's a unique
piece that he
he offers. Hard to explain I
know he cares Uh so that's
probably the first thing cuz you
know so many guys have talent
but the mindset's mindset's the
differentiator and I think in
that instance it's certainly
something that I I think plays
its part. CJ Williams said he
knew the Jags were interested
enough to go back and watch
every game from last season What
did you find about CJ and your
research on him? That is I did
not know that that nugget That
is I I felt like I held
that one close to the vest but
uh nonetheless I think he fits
the
bill for a lot of things things
that I've long appreciated in
wide receiver play Uh with both
the the guys that we drafted at
the position uh they are
extremely
tough extremely good blockers Uh
they are extremely good at
attacking the
football Uh so really excited
about both him and Josh Josh
entering the fry. Would Josh 528
lb squat. Oh man that's
impressive Have you seen that
on film? I I have not seen that
but I have watched his football
play and I can understand
how he's able to do that when
he's got five guys on his back
and he's still standing Uh
that's not all that that
surprising but yeah he is an
impressive human being. Couple
walk-ons late college walk-ons
What does that tell you about
them? Couple walk-ons early You
You
know you got to love it I think
that that is a part to me that
uh says a lot If you can start
there and end in the
conversation of being being a
potential draft
pick It says a lot about uh what
you can overcome being able to
you know when
when your back's against the
wall be able to find your your
path to success And uh certainly
something that we think about
when we're prioritizing guys.
How does Tanner Tanner
fit? I think very clearly he's
got a superpower that he offers
in a real way and that's
catching the football Uh
obviously his production over
over the course of his college
tenure speaks volumes Uh being
one of if not the most
productive pass
catcher uh uh in college history
depending on how you look at
things And uh I
think for how we operate for how
how Trevor um
best operates Having a a big
target like that it isn't a bad
thing especially when it comes
to red
zone play. You mentioned that
the volume Did Did you go in
with that plan Like was that
always in your head that you
wanted to get as many draft
picks and maybe not move around
as much? Yeah that was a big
piece to even even my walk
through in the interview process
A higher volume of draft capital
was what we were seeking And
knowing that the more at bats
you you
have the better probability uh
you'll have for for successful
selections while at the same
time uh you can have a few few
more hit uh misses than you do
hits But
But nonetheless uh it was cool
to lean into that as a part of
this draft
And uh I know with 10 more that
lie in front of us in 20 and 27
as it stands we're going going
to have a healthy three-year run
in terms of count. What was your
uh favorite
or most memorable call from this
past three days? Oh man I don't
know if I can say that on on
on air There there were
definitely some entertaining
moments Uh you always appreciate
those calls Uh knowing that they
can can be uh so meaningful
for the guys that are across the
line And you know while there
were a ton of emotions
uh for them There were also a
ton of emotions on our end and
to see our coaching staff our
scouting staff who have poured
in a ton of time and energy uh
into
coming to ultimately a big big
decision Uh it's really just a
moment where
I I find myself myself being
grateful Uh moment of gratitude
to to be able to be the one to
dial Um but it's it's certainly
a meaningful meaningful moment
and the most
entertaining ones I'll probably
have to keep offline. Now that
your second draft class is
done how much different
different was this process
compared to your first one last
year? You know I think uh
certainly efficient in
comparison uh not
being being in a position where
you have to translate two
different systems uh two
different
languages languages uh it just
allows lines of communication to
be more fluid and so I think
that was a really helpful piece
to to our process and uh one
that I have to
imagine will only continue to
get more refined and better as
we move forward. James how you
compare uh gosh I want to say 3
3 weeks
ago was when I really poured in
Uh that was another one where
where uh our area scout had a
ton of interest Um our undrafted
college
free agent committee uh surfaced
him to to the and got us really
pouring in at a deeper level
across our over the top scouts
scouts uh coordinator level
myself
and Liam um and then if I'm not
mistaken he ended up being uh
the player that was listed in
that annual article um of go
ahead and figure out who this
guy is and uh Brian Xanders
ended up knocking on my door and
after reading it said hey you
know what But I think uh I think
he may be
somebody that is going to become
more publicly aware here soon or
maybe come of interest to others
if they're able to figure it out
as well Um but nonetheless
certainly excited to
bring him into the into the
organization knowing that he's
got uh really a cool
background you know and one that
that um is not all that
different than some of the
others that we drafted and
overcoming the odds and earning
their place And uh you know he
was really really really
effective in rushing the pass or
creating disruption this past
season.
James how do you compare what
you got out of this draft to
what you wanted to get out of
it? Oh that's a great great
question Uh so I can say as a
part of
maybe the day before uh kickoff
on Thursday we ended ended up
putting players in slots across
all 11 picks and uh
can in fact say that uh we were
able to nail 10 of those 11 11
and
we only made 10 selections So uh
that was a pretty fun outcome
knowing that we were able to map
it uh as cleanly as we were I
don't think that uh had had
anything to do with skill but
maybe a little more luck than
that But uh that was a pretty
exciting piece. When guys
are transferring schools schools
so much more now than 5 10 years
ago does that
make the process for you guys a
scouting process and
investigation process any any
harder or any more difficult
than it used to be? It makes it
interesting It makes it a little
bit more of a chase chase while
at the same time you know I when
guys are only in one place for a
short period of time you may
not get a full picture So it's
only a glimpse glimpse typically
So you'd like for there to be uh
a little bit more of a long-term
standing uh position for you to
source intel from and and not
just a some place that they may
have stopped not just
called some version of of a stay
but I think it helps when people
are really intimate with the
player that you're listening to
their perspective on
Um and so that bouncing around
can make it a little more
challenging Well at the same
time now you get a few different
more perspectives on the matter
So uh I don't think it it hurts
uh so to speak but uh yeah it
definitely makes the chase a
little bit more entertaining.
Kind of mapping out the draft
You ever done that before I mean
your time time in LA last season
been able to do it. That was a
fun exercise this
year And um I can say to a
certain degree I
would Uh but I wasn't making
making the decisions in Los
Angeles So that was uh probably
more on my own or off to the
side Um whereas this one was
obviously
I had a little little bit more
control over what direction we
actually went Uh I know that
Jake does that on his own Jake
Tami and and it's fun to uh look
over and
cross reference uh a larger list
of players that he would love to
choose from and
uh have that be a part of the
the conversation But But yeah
that was a a unique one for this
this cycle. Did you expect to be
able to hit it like that? No No
So that
was a fun That was a blast Yeah
Liam and I were just just
laughing about it that you know
that
was an oddity I think I think
that was an outlier I wouldn't
anticipate that being the case
even moving forward. I feel like
I asked last year how would you
you evaluate evaluate your pass
rush after three days of That's
hard to say that it's any
different than where it was
uh you know towards the end of
last season I think the exciting
thing from my vantage point is
we got some really good football
players across that defensive
front and
our our scheme is prepped to tie
not only not only the rush plan
but also the backend
coverage together in a way
that's going to make that really
impactful impactful all these
guys. Yeah that could impact uh
uh just how quickly he's able to
hit the ground running Uh
we'll assess that a little more
closely upon arrival but uh it's
fair question because
it could in fact fact delay his
start to on the grass play.
Everybody else good? Everybody
else is good to go Thank you
James